Guide to the Stanford University, Music Library, Records SC0722
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Music Library, records
1978-2001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Music Library
Stanford University. Libraries. Music Library
SC0722
6.5 Linear Feet
Collection includes minutes, correspondence, memoranda, grant proposals, reports, and other records. Subjects include the planning and construction of a new building, 1980-81; public service, flood control, preservation projects, and other matters, 1978-2001; and a co-operative project with the Library of Congress, New York Public Library, Yale, and Syracuse University to catalog sound recordings, undertaken by the Associated Audio Archives, a sub-group of the Association of Recorded Sound Collections, in the early 1980s.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes minutes, correspondence, memoranda, grant proposals, reports, and other records. Subjects include the planning and construction of a new building, 1980-81; public service, flood control, preservation projects, and other matters, 1978-2001; and a co-operative project with the Library of Congress, New York Public Library, Yale, and Syracuse University to catalog sound recordings, undertaken by the Associated Audio Archives, a sub-group of the Association of Recorded Sound Collections, in the early 1980s.
Music libraries -- California.; Academic libraries -- California.; Stanford University. Music Library; Stanford University. Music Library; Stanford University. Libraries. Music Library; Stanford University. Libraries. Music Library
- Records, Accession ARCH-2006-320
  - Music Library Records
    - Grant proposal: Retrospective Conversion of Music Catalogs of the Associated Music Libraries Group, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Earthquake, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Music Guild - Memorial Gift Program 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Preservation – Music locked stack (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Instrument drawing preservation project, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Rigler Deutsch Record Index, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - SULAIR Funding Needs 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, misc., 1980-83 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Music Dept., minutes, memos, 1991-2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Library Committee: topics, 1985-92 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Library Committee, reports, agenda, minutes, 1981-84 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Library Committee, reports, agenda, minutes, 1979-80 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1979-85 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Ruth Ormondroyd, "The Music Library at Stanford University," 1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, John Howard [RISM Project], 1985-87 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - RISM/Stanford (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - RISM/U.S. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Archive of Recorded Sound Records
    - Record labels (includes photographs of labels) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Associated Audio Archives (AAA) – catalog rules (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - AAA – catalog rules (2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - NEH Proposal [Union Catalog of Pre-LP 78 RPM Recordings], draft, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - AAA – NEH report [A Union Catalog of Commercially Issued pre-"LP" Classical Music and Spoken Word Sound Recordings: a Planning Study] 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - AAA – collections general, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Report on Data Collection for Archival Cataloging of Sound Recordings: A Pilot Project, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Association for Recorded Sound Collections [ARSC] – miscellaneous correspondence, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - AAA – Library of Congress, correspondence, 1975-78 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - AAA – Syracuse, correspondence, 1977-79 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - AAA – expenses (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - AAA – Toronto, correspondence, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - AAA – Yale, correspondence and forms, 1977-79 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - AAA – New York Public Library, correspondence and forms, 1975-78 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - AAA – Stanford, correspondence, memoranda, and forms, 1975-79 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - AAA – general correspondence, 1976-78 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Rutgers Project for Cataloging Jazz Recordings, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - AAA – Union List of Periodicals (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - AAA – correspondence, 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - AAA – manual catalog (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - AAA – production (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - AAA – cataloging rules (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - AAA – access (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - AAA – collection survey (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Grant proposal: Union List of Sound Records 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Minutes [grant committee] 1976-77 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - AAA – general [correspondence and other records] 1976-77 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - AAA – consultant's report 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - AAA – position papers 1976-77 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - AAA – production (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - AAA – consultants data 1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - AAA (Hewlett Foundation) Accounts paid (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - AAA (Hewlett Foundation) report (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - AAA (Hewlett Foundation) grant application 1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - AAA (Hewlett Foundation) letters of participation in NEH project (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - NEH grant, letters of support/participation, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Final report [Union Catalog of Commercially Issued pre-"LP" Classical Music…] 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - AAA – BALLOTS (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - David Hall – on cataloging rules 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - AAA – Consultant: Butler (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - AAA – Intro to cataloging rules (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - AAA guests (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - AAA – Mi-Kal County-Matic Inc., correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - AAA (Hewlett) – Mi-Kal (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - AAA: NEH grant application [Union Catalog of Commercially Issued pre-"LP" Classical Music…] 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - AAA – post NEH 1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - AAA: fundraising (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - AAA (Hewlett) – Warner Bros., 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - AAA (Hewlett) – NEH proposal, correspondence re, 1978-79 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - AAA (Hewlett) – Autographics (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - AAA (Hewlett) – general (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - AAA (Hewlett) – consultant (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - AAA (correspondence, memos, reports, etc.) 1974-75 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Hewlett Foundation, 1978-79 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - RDI Project – historical (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Record Format Specifications for the Pre-LP Sounding Recordings Project for the ARSC, Final Report, July 1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Evaluation of Data Processing Alternatives for a National Music Data Base, December 1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Evaluation of Data Processing Alternatives for a National Music Data Base, January 1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - A Comprehensive Union Catalog for Sound Recordings; a Proposal by AAA to RLG, May 10, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - ARSC/AAA – Minutes, memos, correspondence, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Other data bases – mostly correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - AAA – correspondence 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Name authority (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Issue of multiple sides (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1980-81 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 1979 Grant application and correspondence, 1980-81 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Miscellany (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - The Role of Automated Systems in the Union Catalog of Sound Recordings Project [Butler Associates], Aug. 1977 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - AAA – historical, 1978-79 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Report on Data Collection for Archival Cataloging of Sound Recordings: a Pilot Project, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - RLG/AAA – correspondence and memos, 1982-83 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - RLG (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - ARSC/AAA Project Reports, Sept. 1982-July 1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - ARSC/AAA Project Reports, Jan.-August 1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - ARSC/AAA Project Reports, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Institute for Jazz Studies (Rutgers) NEH Grant Proposal 1983 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Assorted correspondence, reports, etc., 1983-84 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2008-113
  - Archive of Recorded Sound (ARS) – background and program, 1979-83 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Program for the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound," Nov. 14, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ARS – funding matters, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Structural Evaluation of the Knoll, with related documents, 1982-83 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Planning documents 1982-83 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Planning documents 1982-83 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Planning documents 1982-83 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Planning documents – architectural drawings, plans (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2015-108
  - Architectural drawings and correspondence re space planning for music library, 1980s (Box 1)